<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rchaeology</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Rchaeology</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rchaeology.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Into the Fediverse</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/posts/2023/06/into-the-fediverse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rchaeology.github.io/posts/2023/06/into-the-fediverse/</guid><description>By now you have most likely heard of the Fediverse. Lately it has gained momentum due to the acquisition of Twitter and its subsequent demise, causing so-called &amp;lsquo;migrations&amp;rsquo; to other platforms. Among them, Mastodon, one small part of the Fediverse.
If not, or you want to learn more, see below. The Rchaeology community now has a Mastodon account and a chat on Element/Matrix (Slack alternative). Both are hosted on archaeo.social. Both are open source!</description></item><item><title>Archaeology</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/resources/archaeology/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 20:15:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rchaeology.github.io/resources/archaeology/</guid><description>Purpose Here you will find a list of resources with very archaeology-specific applications, including slides, textbooks, and packages. You will be able to find a much more comprehensive list of resources on Ben Marwick&amp;rsquo;s CRAN Task View for archaeology.
&amp;#x1f4e6; Packages install.packages()
archdata rcarbon c14bazAAR evoarchdata zooaRch leastcostpath 👩‍🏫 Slides Statistical inference and data exploration for archaeologists - Ben Marwick
&amp;#x1f4bb; Sites and Blogs Archaeoinformatics - Sophie Schmidt
Plotting dental inventory with ggplot2 - Bjørn Peare Bartholdy</description></item><item><title>print('Hello World')</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/posts/2021/11/printhello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rchaeology.github.io/posts/2021/11/printhello-world/</guid><description>New Website To increase our visibility, we have launched a new website (which you have obviously already found) using the Hello Friend NG Hugo theme, with some slight tweaks.
Goals With this new platform, we aim to provide a convenient, centralised location for all your Rchaeological needs, from general R resources for beginners, to more advanced R topics in archaeology and related disciplines.
We will offer occasional posts on various topics on a completely unpredictable schedule.</description></item><item><title>Beginners</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/resources/beginners/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:04:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rchaeology.github.io/resources/beginners/</guid><description>&amp;#x1f44b; Welcome So you want to learn R? Here are some resources that will help you on your jouRney to awesomeness!
&amp;#x1f4bb; Installing R and RStudio Danielle Navarro slides and youtube video &amp;#x2328;&amp;#xfe0f; Console swirl R package # enter the following in the R console install.packages(&amp;#34;swirl&amp;#34;) library(&amp;#34;swirl&amp;#34;) &amp;#x1f3eb; Online Courses and Tutorials Getting Started with R - free course by R for the Rest of Us
Data carpentry
R for Social Scientists R for Ecologists R for beginners by Ihnwhi Heo, Duco Veen, and Rens van de Schoot</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 13:45:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rchaeology.github.io/about/</guid><description>Rchaeology Rchaeology is a community for archaeologists who use, and want to learn R statistical software.
Goals We aspire to make the R programming language accessible to all archaeologists, and provide an open, welcoming community for all those who are interested in learning. We also want to help Rchaeologists find one another, whether for collaboration, getting help with field-specific R questions, or just to nerd out and chat about R.</description></item></channel></rss>