<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rchaeology</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Rchaeology</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rchaeology.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blogging with R Markdown</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/posts/2021/09/blogging-with-r-markdown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rchaeology.github.io/posts/2021/09/blogging-with-r-markdown/</guid><description>Contributing There are multiple ways to contribute a blog post.
The simplest way is to contact us, and provide a blog post in whatever format you feel comfortable writing.
To streamline the process, providing an Rmd document with the blog post will make the process quicker.
The best quickest way to contribute, is to fork the repository on GitHub, create the blog post, and submit a pull request.</description></item><item><title>Beginners</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/resources/beginners/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:04:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rchaeology.github.io/resources/beginners/</guid><description>👋 Welcome So you want to learn R? Here are some resources that will help you on your jouRney to awesomeness!
🧑‍💻 Installing R and RStudio Danielle Navarro slides and youtube video ⌨️ Console swirl R package # enter the following in the R console install.packages(&amp;quot;swirl&amp;quot;) library(&amp;quot;swirl&amp;quot;) 🧑‍🏫 Online Courses Getting Started with R - free course by R for the Rest of Us</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://rchaeology.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 13:45:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rchaeology.github.io/about/</guid><description>Rchaeology Rchaeology is a community for archaeologists who use, and want to learn R statistical software.
Goals We aspire to make the R programming language accessible to all archaeologists, and provide an open, welcoming community for all those who are interested in learning. We also want to help Rchaeologists find one another, whether for collaboration, getting help with field-specific R questions, or just to nerd out and chat about R.</description></item></channel></rss>